I see.
The restoration of your right
to succeed the throne?
Yes. I've been removed from my duties
as princess for a long time,
so I thought I should reintroduce
myself to the spirit-faithful.
I see! That is quite admirable.
It seems our tomboy princess
has settled down at last.
Do you intend to assume the role
of our future queen from now on?
Yes... I do.
Is she mad?
We've never had a queen, much less
a royal who couldn't use magic!
The king isn't even forty years old yet.
He could still produce
a new heir if he tried.
Yes, a king has an obligation to produce
and raise his heir, for crying out loud!
He must have some profound idea in mind
that we lower classes could never fathom.
Either that,
or he just really wants
Princess Anisphia to be queen.
Regardless of what the king may be thinking,
I intend to carry out my duties
respectably as the next in line.
I would greatly appreciate your cooperation.
You have made your determination
quite clear to us.
We look forward to seeing how
you conduct yourself henceforth.
Yes. I humbly request your
guidance and encouragement.
Indeed.
However, may I say just one thing?
Your... "magicology," was it?
It is unacceptable.
To give magic, a blessing granted
only to us, to mere commoners
would render the authority of
the nobility and royalty useless.
Do you understand?
No need for concern.
The princess has always
loved magic, after all.
Which means she will need to think of a way
to give magic to the next generation.
Exactly. The royal family
exists for the purpose
of inheriting the gift of
magic from the spirits.
Meaning it would be ideal for the princess
to produce an heir as soon as possible.
In that case, we shall
have to choose a partner
close to her age from a high-ranking family.
At this point, why prioritize status?
We can just choose someone with
an exceptional talent for magic.
Then there's no need to worry
about his age, either.
Indeed. We should keep a
few candidates on hand.
Luckily, the princess seems
to be in magnificent health.
That said, I suppose internal stability
should be our first priority.
True.
Yes, but we must waste no time...
It's okay.
I'm perfectly fine.
The Magical Revolution
of the Reincarnated Princess and the Genius Young Lady
Here you go.
Thank you.
You've truly begun
to look the part of a maid.
I'm still in training...
But I have you to thank, Miss Ilia.
You have been an apprentice
worth teaching, Lainie.
Miss Anis, may I have some time
to speak with you tomorrow?
Ilia and Lainie, I'd like you there, as well.
Um, I have Tilty's medical exam tomorrow...
I'll reschedule it.
Thank you.
I've found what it is that I must do.
And I want you, along with your father
and mother, to hear it first.
Ah, there you are, Anis.
Father, who is she?
Pleased to meet you, Your Highness.
I'm Lumi.
If I called myself a spirit contractor,
would you understand?
Huh?! But... what is a spirit
contractor doing here?
Your Majesties, thank you for making time
to meet with me today.
It's no bother at all.
But I do wonder what it
is you want to tell us...
I have a favor I wish to ask of you.
Uh-huh...
Miss Lumi has determined that I meet the
requirements to forge a spirit contract.
What?!
Huh? A s-spirit contract? Euphie?
Yes.
She is the only one in the world right now
with the qualifications and will to do it.
Are you serious?
Even knowing the truth of what
spirit contractors are?!
Yes.
Becoming a spirit contractor will make it
difficult for you to live a normal life.
What do you mean by that?
How old does Miss Lumi look to you?
How old? About the same as me?
She still looks exactly the way
she did when we first met her.
That was decades ago.
So spirit contractors... never age?
Well, yes, but it's more than just that.
In exchange for receiving great power,
the contract dictates
that you will eventually
become a spirit yourself.
You'll... become a spirit?
My real name is Lumielle René Palettia.
In other words, I'm your ancestor.
Ancestor? You mean...
I had a prince consort, too.
He was a good man. A very good man.
There were times when I wished
I could live with him forever.
But...
The difference between our lifespans
killed any hope of that.
Once you become a spirit,
all desires you had as a human disappear.
There's no more need
for memories or emotions.
Can you imagine that? You forget everything.
The way they smile at you in exasperation,
the sound of their voice
softly calling your name,
the warmth you feel when
they shyly touch you...
You forget all of it.
However you may try
to preserve it all in writing,
it only survives on paper.
It becomes no more than a record
with no feelings attached to it.
You even forget that you forgot it.
You lose your human body, your human life,
and in time, even your human soul...
and find yourself trapped
in eternal solitude.
That's... the truth of the spirit contract?
Knowing that, do you still wish to forge one?
Yes. The spirit contract
is essential in fulfilling my wish.
Your Majesty, once I have
completed the spirit contract,
I would like you to adopt me
into the royal family
and grant me the right
to inherit the throne.
What?
W-Wait, wait! What are you saying?!
Adopt you?! Why would you ask that?!
Grantz! What's the meaning of this?!
Why would Euphyllia ask such a thing?!
I never gave her my blessing to ask this.
But you know she isn't the type
to take no for an answer.
She is my daughter.
Euphie... Why would you...
Because I cannot allow you to become queen.
Wh-Why not?
What do you mean by that, Euphyllia?
Miss Anis will never be accepted
by the nobility of this kingdom,
for the sole reason that
she cannot use magic.
And that's why you want me to
give you the right to succeed?
I acknowledge that you
have remarkable talent.
But even if we adopt you, that doesn't
guarantee the nobles will accept you!
That's what the spirit contract is for.
If I achieve the same thing
our founding king did,
I can convince the spirit-faithful
to accept me.
Euphie, why?
So that you won't have to be queen.
Wait... Hang on!
I never asked you to do this!
I know. This is a promise
that I made my own decision to fulfill.
I don't want you to become queen.
Are you serious about this?
But you won't be human anymore!
You'll lose everyone, forget everything,
and be alone for the rest of eternity!
You can't do that!
I'd rather be queen than let you...
Do you truly believe that you can
lead this kingdom as its queen?
You're right. I don't have
the ability to use magic.
And I know the nobles of this
kingdom will never accept me.
But that's no reason for you
to take this upon yourself!
Still, if I become queen,
I'll be able to keep your dream alive.
Don't you love magic and want to share it
so that more people can understand
how wonderful it is?!
Wasn't that your dream?!
My dream...
I want you to achieve your dream.
Your dream will bring
prosperity to this kingdom.
Please allow me to share
your dream with you.
For you to be free is my hope and wish.
So, Miss Anis, please take my hand.
No...
Don't talk like that!
Don't make me depend on you!
Miss Anis?
I'm the princess!
Whether they accept me or not,
I'm this kingdom's princess!
If you take even that away from me...
What value will I have left?
Anis...
Wait, Anis!
Anisphia!
What in the world are you doing?
Tilty... Why...
You're the one who told me
to make a house call.
Do you have any idea what a spectacle
you're making of yourself?
I could tell it was you
from inside my carriage.
Ugh, you're such a pain.
Can you stand?
Huh?
What did I tell you?
You're making a scene. Come on.
Right...
Go home once you've calmed down.
Or should I call someone to come get you?
Sorry. Don't do that.
Not yet.
What a pain...
Aren't you supposed to just silently
comfort me at times like this?
What do you expect out of me?
Go home before this blows up into
a big mess. You're a nuisance.
A nuisance...
I'm sorry, okay?
You're really throwing me off here...
Stay as long as you want.
Okay.
But when someone comes for you, go home.
Will anyone come?
If they don't, you could
just stay here, right?
I'll hear you out, at least
whenever I have the time.
I see.
I thought you didn't care about
your right to the throne.
I didn't care.
But Al isn't around anymore.
I'm the one who has to take on
the responsibility of ruling.
If I don't, I have no value as a princess.
So how could she tell me I don't
have to be queen after all this?
But I have to give in.
They'll never accept me.
Why do you need them to accept you?
Huh?
A stupid father who dumps all the
responsibility on his daughter...
A bunch of stupid nobles who give thanks
for some moldy old traditions...
A stupid kingdom that
doesn't appreciate you...
Why do you need any of them to accept you?
But... But still...
Oh, come on...
Why don't you just ditch this kingdom?
Throw away your role
and your right to the throne,
and go somewhere completely
different to study magic.
You don't need to be here to do that, right?
I can't.
If you'd be missing any documents
or materials, I can help you.
It might be nice to travel
to all kinds of places together.
We could study the magic and curses
they have in other countries,
eat some delicious foods here and there,
and maybe con some money out of
evil nobles and corrupt merchants.
That sounds nice.
But we can't.
I still can't throw it away.
I can't throw away the fact
that I'm a princess.
I see.
Tilty! Are you in there?
If you are, please answer me!
Someone came for you after all.
Ready?
Miss Anis...
I'll leave the room. Tell me before you go.
I'm very sorry for all the trouble.
Just leave me alone.
I can't do that!
Why are you making that face?
That's the first time you've
expressed anger toward me.
Huh?
Being a princess was much more important
to you than I realized, wasn't it?
You're not fair, Euphie!
I wanted the ability to use magic, too!
Then I wouldn't have to lose
anyone... or anything...
Why do you have to deprive me
of my role as princess now?!
It's my duty... and it's all I have left!
Even if no one approves
or expects anything of me,
I'm the princess of this kingdom!
I'm the daughter of my mother and father!
I can still keep trying hard...
I can try harder!
So don't make me someone nobody needs!
It's okay. I'm perfectly fine.
You're obviously not fine at all!
Someone who values others before herself,
who can't leave them on their own,
who'd even sacrifice herself for them...
To be rejected and hated by everyone...
There's no way you're fine with that!
Stop.
None of this is your fault!
This kingdom where you can't make anyone
happy without magic is to blame!
But even so, this is the kingdom that my
mother and father wanted to protect!
And all I can do is ruin that...
But you have protected it.
With the power of magic that
you had more faith in than anyone.
You care about this kingdom
more than anyone,
and you've fought for it
by yourself all this time.
Even without anyone's approval,
you made your very own
kind of magic a reality.
You have my affirmation
above all others, Miss Anis.
It's okay now. You've done enough.
I can give up now.
Euphie, the one I admire most
of all, gave me her approval.
That's more than rewarding enough.
Miss Anis?
I still can't do it.
I don't want to sacrifice you.
My dream can't even begin
to compare to your life.
But—
I know you won't back down,
I know how you feel,
and I know what you're saying.
So... let's have a duel.
That's how you can convince me.
Very well.
Episode Eleven
The Spirit Contract of Despair and Determination
Episode Twelve
Their Magical Revolution